Guide to the Charles Wilkes Papers, 1816-1876 RL.01383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
North Carolina. Wages. Gold Miners, 1849 Feb. 17; 1849 Mar. 21.
North Carolina. Wages. Millwrights, 1854 Feb. 1
North Carolina. Wages. Negroes, 1854 Jan. 13; 1854 Mar. 5.
North Carolina. Wages. Stonemasons, 1854 Jan. 18
North Carolina. Wheat 1858 July 5
North Carolina. Whetstones Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 11)
North Carolina Central Railroad, 1858 Mar. 16; 1858 Dec.; 1859 Jan. 25; 1859 June 13; 1859 June 29; 1859 July 3; 1859 July 10; 1859 July 20; 1859 July 21; 1859 July 28; 1859 Aug. 6; 1859 Aug. 7; 1859 Aug. 15; 1859 Aug. 17; 1859 Sept. 9; 1859 Sept. 14; 1859 Sept. 24; 1859 Oct. 24.
North Pacific Surveying and Exploring Expedition 1852 Oct. 20; 1853 May 31.
Oaths of Allegiance. Reconstruction, 1865 May 28
Observatories 1829 Jan. 2
Observatories. Australia 1839 Dec. 10
Ocean Currents 1844 Nov. 17; 1848 Apr. 25; 1858 June 25; Miscellany: Undated.
Ocean Temperature 1858 July 5; 1858 July 8; 1858 July 14.
Ocean Travel 1826 Feb. 19
Oceanography 1838 June 3
O'Connell, Sir Maurice Charles Philip [?] 1840 [?](#5)
Ogden, Peter Skene 1840 Oct. 18
Ohio. Cincinnati. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XII)
Ohio. Cleveland. Description and Travel 1852 Aug. 30; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XII).
Ohio. Cleveland. Hotels. American Hotel 1852 Aug. 30
Ohio. Coal Mines and Mining, 1856 Nov. 19
Ohio. Columbus. Description and Travel, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Ohio. Description and Travel, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Ohio. Foundries. Bellaire 1855[?]
Ohio. Ohio City Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII, p. 136)
Ohio. Railroad Bridges 1853 Nov. 9; 1858 Apr. 2; 1858 May 5; 1858 Nov. 7.
Ohio. Railroads 1852 Apr. 2; 1852 May 20; 1852 June 10; 1852 June 17; 1852 July 25; 1852 Aug. 9; 1852 Aug. 24; 1852 Aug. 26; 1852 Sept. 2; 1852 Sept. 12; 1852 Oct. 18; 1852 Nov. 1; 1853 Nov. 23; 1854 Nov. 29.
Ohio. Sandusky. Description and Travel, 1852 Aug. 16
Ohio. Tunnels 1855 Dec. 23; 1856 Apr. 20; 1858 Dec. 31.
Ohio. Zanesville. Description and Travel 1852 Aug. 20; 1855 Apr. 5.
Ohio. Zanesville. Maps Printed Material: 1855 Mar.
Ohio and Pennsylvania Railroad Company, 1851 Sept. 15
Oil Industries 1850 Oct. 29
Oliver, Henry Kemble 1850 Oct. 22
Ombrosi, James Letter to: 1830 Dec. 6; 1830 Nov. 4; 1830 Nov. 5; 1830 Nov. 9; 1830 Dec. 8.
Opera. France 1836 Oct. 9
Opera. New York. New York Writings: "Theatres," pp. 1-2
Opium Trade 1850 Oct. 31; 1851 Dec. 8.
Oregon. Description and Travel, 1841 May 20
Oregon. Willamette Valley 1840 May 20
Oregon Question 1845 Dec. 12; 1846 Mar. 13.
Oregon Territory 1849 Mar. 2
Osborne, James W. 1849 June; 1850 Feb. 3; 1850 Feb. 16; 1850 Feb. 22; 1850 Mar. 7; 1851 Aug. 6; 1856 Dec. 21; 1857 Feb. 2; 1858 Mar. 31; 1858 Apr. 15; 1858 Apr. 21; 1858 Oct. 29; 1858 Nov. 14; 1859 Jan. 2; 1859 Feb. 27; 1859 Mar. 13; 1867 Sept. 11; 1868 Feb. 3; 1873 May 27
Owens, Robert Dale 1849 Mar. 22; 1853 Aug. 1.
Páez, José Antonio 1848 July 6; 1848 July 24.
Page, Charles Grafton 1836 Nov. 3
Panama. Colón. Description and Travel, 1859 Aug. 16
Panama. Foreign Relations. United States 1826 Mar. 17
Panama. Panama Canal 1849 Dec. 22 (on letter of 1850 Mar. 14)
Parke, John Grubb 1863 Mar. 7; 1863 Mar. 16; 1871 Dec. 3.
Parker, Amasa Junius (1807-1890), 1870 June 8
Parker, Foxhall Alexander (?-1857) [?], 1830 Oct. 4; 1830 Oct. 12; 1830 Nov. 9; 1830 Dec. 6; 1830 Dec. 8; 1830 Dec. 21; 1831 Jan. 11; 1831 Jan. 30.
Parker, Joel (1795-1875) Writings: "The Surrender of Mason and Slidell," pp. 3-4)
Parker, Peter 1850 Sept. 2; 1850 Sept. 14; 1850 Oct. 2; 1851 Dec. 8.
Parks. Maryland. Baltimore. Howard Park, Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, pp. 265-266
Parks. New York. New York. Central Park, Writings: Fire Department, pp. 7 and following; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XVI).
Patronage. Political Miscellany: 1862 [?] (2)
Paulding, Hiram 1849 Jan. 23; 1862 Aug. 1; 1862 Aug. 9; 1862 Aug. 23; 1863 Jan. 30; 1863 Feb. 4; 1863 Feb. 12.
Paulding, Hiram [?] 1847 July 7
Paulding, James Kirke Letter to: 1816 May 6; Letter to: 1839 Feb. 23[?]; 1818 Jan. 19; 1838 July 19; 1838 Aug. 18; 1839 Dec. 2; 1840 Oct. 18; 1841; 1842 June 18; 1844 Oct. 21; 1844 Nov. 17; 1845 Feb. 10; 1845 Feb. 23.
Paulding, James Kirke [?] 1838 ca. July
Peace 1836 Mar. 14
Peale, Titian Ramsay 1845[?] Feb. 4; 1848 Apr. 13; 1849 Oct. 24; 1852 Nov. 22; 1852 Nov. 27; 1857 Mar. 9.
Pearce, James Alfred Letter to: 1849 Dec. 18; Letter to: 1857 Jan. 19; Letter to: 1860 Jan. 3; 1849 July 9; 1850 Jan. 21; 1850 July 6; 1852 June 21; 1852 Nov. 27; 1852 Dec. 8; 1853 Aug. 2 (enclosed with letter of Aug. 4); 1853 Aug. 11; 1855 Aug. 8; 1856 Dec. 18; 1856 Dec. 21
Pearl Fisheries Printed Material: 1852 May 22
Pearson, George F. 1862 Oct. 23; 1862 Nov. 4.
Peirce, Benjamin (1809-1880) [?], 1857 May 26
Pendulum. Experiments 1841 Feb. 14
Pennsylvania. Altoona. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter II)
Pennsylvania. Coal Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Pennsylvania. Coal Mines and Mining, 1846 Jan. 14
Pennsylvania. Commerce Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Pennsylvania. Description and Travel, 1852 Aug. 16; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters I and II).
Pennsylvania. Erie. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Pennsylvania. Erie. Land Plats, 1850 Feb. 23
Pennsylvania. Erie. Petroleum Wells Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Pennsylvania. Iron Industry and Trade, 1868 Jan. 17; 1868 Feb. 3; 1874 [?].
Pennsylvania. Philadelphia. Civil War, 1863 June 17
Philadelphia. Stock Exchange, Printed Material: 1863 May 4
Pennsylvania. Pittsburgh Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter II)
Pennsylvania. Politics and Government, 1850 July 1
Pennsylvania. Philadelphia. Railroads, Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p.263
Pennsylvania. Philadelphia. Rawle Family 1825[?] Aug. 5
Pennsylvania. Springs (Resorts). Bedford Springs 1825 Aug. 12; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter I).
Pennsylvania. Venango County. Land Plats 1835 Dec. 25
Pensions. Military 1851 Nov. 24
Periodicals. American Review Printed Material: 1855 Nov. 1
Perry, Matthew Calbraith Letter to: 1836 Nov. 18; 1847 Dec. 21; 1848 Jan. 27; 1848 Feb. 21; 1848 Mar. 2; 1848 Mar. 30; 1861 May 7.
Persico, E. Luigi 1830 Oct. 25
Peru. Americans in 1839 July 3
Peru. Commerce 1826 Feb. 4
Peru. Clothing and Dress 1823 Jan. [?]
Peru. Description and Travel, 1839 July 3
Peru. Harbors 1825 Nov. 25
Peru. Lima. Burial 1823 Jan. [?]
Peru. Lima. Description and Travel, 1823 Jan. [?]
Peru. Lima. Earthquakes 1823 Jan. [?]
Peru. Lima. Social Life and Customs, 1839 July 3
Peru. Politics and Government, 1825 Nov. 25; 1839 June 12.
Philippine Islands. Commerce, 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Description and Travel 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Ducks 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Manila. Balls (Parties) 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Manila. Cigar Manufacture and Trade 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Manila. Dinners and Dining 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Manila. Earthquakes 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Population, 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Rope Makers, 1851 Jan. 27
Philippine Islands. Volcanoes, 1851 Jan. 27
Phytogeography 1850 Nov. 30
Pickering, Charles 1836 Nov. 3; 1842 Aug. 28; 1852 July 17; 1852 Nov. 22; 1852 Nov. 27; 1853 June 20; 1857 Jan. 31; 1857 Feb. 7; 1857 May 26; 1859 July 19; 1859 July 28; 1859 Aug. 1; 1860 Jan. 7; 1871 May 12; 1873 Jan. 30; Miscellany: 1852 June 14.
Pico Alto 1830 July 17
Piedmont Railroad 1856 May 28
Pierce, Franklin 1852 Nov. 4; 1854 Mar. 30; 1856 Dec. 21.
Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth (1812-1899) 1849 Oct. 13
Pinkney, Ninian 1850 Mar. 4
Pirates. Chinese 1850 Oct. 2; 1850 Dec. 29; 1851 Mar. 31; 1851 Dec. 8.
Pirates. Pescadores 1851 July 20
Pittsburg, Maysville and Cincinnati Railroad Company 1853 Sept. 25
Plantations. South Carolina 1826 Feb. 22; 1851 Nov. 3.
Planters. South Carolina 1826 Feb. 22
Plants 1850 Dec. 13; 1852 July 17.
Poinsett, Joel Roberts Letter to: 1838 Apr. 4; Letter to: 1838 July 19; Letter to: Undated (in letter of 1838 June 16); 1828 Mar. 18; 1838 Jan. 22; 1838 Feb. 5; 1838 June 5; 1838 Aug. 18; 1838 Sept. 26; 1842 June 20; 1844 Oct. 29; Miscellany: 1838.
Political Parties. Democratic 1852 Nov. 11; 1876 Mar. 26.
Political Parties. Democratic. New York, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV, pp. 153-154)
Political Parties. Democratic. North Carolina 1858 Apr. 15
Political Parties. Loco Foco. Georgia, 1849 Dec. 21
Political Parties. Republican. North Carolina 1876 Mar. 26
Political Parties. Whig 1852 Nov. 2; 1852 Nov. 5.
Polk, James Knox 1844 Nov. 22; 1845 Dec. 12; 1849 Mar. 22; 1849 June.
Polk, Sarah (Childress) 1846 July 24
Portales, Diego 1839 June 12
Porter, David 1826 Jan. 26; 1830 July 17; 1830 Aug. 19; 1830 Sept. 12; 1830 Oct. 4; 1830 Dec. 6.
Porter, David Dixon 1862 Aug. 5; 1862 Aug. 7; 1863 Feb. 18; 1863 Mar. 18; 1870 Sept. 29; 1870 Dec. 9.
Porter, David Dixon [?] 1863 Mar. 7; 1863 Mar. 15.
Porter, Fitz John 1862 Oct. 22; 1862 Nov. 23; 1862 Nov. 30; 1862 Dec. 2; 1863 Jan. 4; 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan. 23 (2); 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Jan. 28; 1863 Feb. 12; 1863 Feb. 18; 1863 Feb. 22; 1863 Apr. 6 (with letter of Apr. 4).
Portland Society of Natural History, 1850 Mar. 16
Portraits 1850 Mar. 5; 1850 June; 1850 Sept. 6.
Portugal. Commerce 1850 Dec. 29
Portugal. Foreign Relations. China, 1850 June 23
Portugal. Navy 1850 Oct. 31
Postal Service 1850 Oct. 31; 1851 Nov. 17.
Postal Service. Foreign Mail 1850 Dec. 3
Preble George Henry 1863 Feb. 24
Presidential Elections. 1844 1844 Dec. 27
Presidential Elections. 1848 1848 Nov. 9
Presidential Elections. 1852 1852 Nov. 2; 1852 Nov. 4; 1852 Nov. 5.
Presidential Elections. 1856 1856 July 24
Presidential Elections. 1864 Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV, pp. 1853-154)
Preston, William Ballard 1849 Mar. 10; 1849 Mar. 31; 1849 May 21; 1849 July 9; 1849 Oct. 8; 1849 Oct. 10; 1849 Dec. 3; 1850 Jan. 21; 1850 Mar. 28; 1850 May 3; 1850 Oct. 2; 1850 Oct. 21.
Prieto, Joaquín 1839 June 12
Prize Money Printed Material: 1865 Mar. 1
Prizes 1862 Aug. 7
Processions 1848 Apr. 12; 1848 Apr. 13.
Projectiles 1847 Mar. 8
Propellers 1846 Feb. 17
Protestant Episcopal Church. District of Columbia. Washington. St. John's Church 1825 Mar. 22
Protestant Episcopal Church. New York. New York. Trinity Episcopal Church Legal Papers: 1862 Mar. 25; Writings: "Churches," p. 1 (2 sides).
Protestant Episcopal Church. North Carolina. Charlotte. St. Peter's Episcopal Church 1875 Feb. 7; 1875 Mar. 14.
Public Libraries 1859 Aug.
Pyrites 1853 Oct. 23
Pyrites. North Carolina Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 14
Quackenbush, Stephen Platt Letter to: 1862 Aug. 27
Quarantine 1830 Sept. 18
Quarantine. Algeria. Algiers 1830[?] Sept. 3
Quarantine. Italy. Naples 1830 Sept. 18
Races of Man, 1852 Feb. 13
Radford, William (1809-1890, 1862 Aug. 23
Railroad Bridges. Ohio 1853 Nov. 9; 1858 Apr. 2; 1858 May 5; 1858 Nov. 7.
Railroads 1851 June 11; 1859 July 11.
Railroads. District of Columbia. Washington 1871 Sept. 8; 1873 Nov. 3; 1873 Nov. 9.
Railroads. Maryland. Baltimore Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p.264
Railroads. New Jersey 1849 Sept. 7
Railroads. New Jersey. Newark Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p.264
Railroads. New York. New York Writings: "Railways"
Railroads. North Carolina 1857 Jan. 3; 1859 Feb. 27; 1860 Jan. 2; 1860 Nov. 27; 1865 May 20; 1865 May 28; 1865 June 20; 1866 Dec. 14; 1872 Nov. 15; 1876 Apr. 8; Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 2, 12, 14).
Railroads. Ohio 1852 Apr. 2; 1852 May 20; 1852 June 10; 1852 June 17; 1852 July 25; 1852 Aug. 9; 1852 Aug. 24; 1852 Aug. 26; 1852 Sept. 2; 1852 Sept. 12; 1852 Oct. 18; 1852 Nov. 1; 1853 Nov. 23; 1854 Nov. 29.
Railroads. Pennsylvania. Philadelphia, Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p.263
Railroads. Strikes 1857 Dec. 25
Railroads. Surveying 1852 Feb. 1
Railroads. Transcontinental 1849 Apr. 24; 1849 May 15; 1849 July 18; 1849 Sept. 18; 1856 Mar. 18.
Railroads. Virginia 1865 June 20
Ransom, Mathew Whitaker 1876 Feb. 21
Rape 1849 May 17
Raphall, Morris Jacob 1850 Apr. 12
Rawle family. Pennsylvania. Philadelphia 1825[?] Aug. 5
Read, George Campbell [?] 1849 June 11
Reconstruction 1867 Feb. 20; 1867 Feb. 21; 1867 Mar. 4.
Reconstruction. Economic Aspects 1867 Feb. 21; 1867 Mar. 4.
Reconstruction. North Carolina 1865 May 20; 1865 May 28; 1865 June 20; 1866 Mar. 28; 1866 Dec. 14; 1868 Feb. 3; 1870 Aug. 3.
Reed Mining Company 1854 Jan. 10
Renwick, Edward Sabine 1843 July 21; 1843 Aug. 16; 1843 Oct. 7; 1843 Oct. 23; 1843 Oct. 27; 1844 Jan. 18; 1844 Feb. 6; 1844 Apr. 19; 1844 Oct. 12; 1844; 1845 Feb. 3; 1845 Feb. 23; 1846 Apr. 22; 1849 Feb. 1.
Renwick, Henry ("Harry") Brevoort, 1834 Dec. 27; 1837 Dec. 29; 1837 Dec. 31; 1838 Jan. 3; 1838 Jan. 6; 1843 (scattered); 1844 Jan. 28; 1844 Feb. 15; 1844 Feb. 17; 1844 Mar. 2; 1844 May 7; 1844 May 15; 1844 May 21; 1844 June 19; 1844 July 26; 1844; 1845 Feb. 10; 1845 July 3; 1847 Dec. 21; 1
Renwick, James (1792-1863) Letter to: 1846 Jan. 20; Letter to: 1850 Jan. 21; Letter to: Undated (on verso of letter dated 1838 Nov. 29; 1825 Mar. 21; 1834 Jan. 14; 1834 Feb. 21; 1834 Mar. 15; 1834 Mar. 22; 1836 May 27; 1837 Sept. 2; 1838 June 8; 1838 June 11; 1842 Mar. 4; 1842 Dec.
Renwick, James (1818-1895) 1836 Sept. 7; 1837 Mar. 16; 1842 Oct. 18; 1843 July 21; 1848 Nov. 8; 1849 Feb. 1; 1849 Apr. 17; 1849 May 3; 1850 Mar. 4; 1850 June 23; 1852 Feb. 24; 1853 Sept. 6.
Resorts. Italy 1830 Nov. 5
Resorts. New England 1848 June 16
Resorts. New York 1848 June 16
Resorts. Rhode Island. Newport 1848 July 9; 1848 July 12; 1848 July 14; 1848 July 22; 1848 July 26; 1848 July 29; 1848 July 31; 1848 July; 1848 Aug. 1; 1848 Aug. 4; 1850 Sept. 25; 1850 Oct. 1.
Rhett family. South Carolina 1860 Nov. 8
Rhode Island. Hotels. Bristol Ferry House Printed Material: 1856 [?]
Rhode Island. Newport. Resorts, 1848 July 9; 1848 July 12; 1848 July 14; 1848 July 22; 1848 July 26; 1848 July 29; 1848 July 31; 1848 July; 1848 Aug. 1; 1848 Aug. 4; 1850 Sept. 25; 1850 Oct. 1.
Richard(s), John H. 1852 Nov. 12 (on letter of Nov. 11); 1852 Nov. 17.
Richardson, Sir John (1787-1865), 1849 June 8
Richmond, Elkanah Dean 1859 Feb. 14
Ridgely, Charles Goodwin 1838 May 19; 1838 June 5.
Ridgely, Daniely Bowly 1863 Mar. 6; 1863 Mar. 9.
Rifles 1847 Apr. 30
Ringgold, Cadwalader 1838 May 19; 1838 May 26; 1838 June 4; 1838 July 23; 1843 Nov. 3; 1852 Dec. 8; 1857 July 30; Legal Papers: 1857 Oct. 21.
Riots. New York 1834 July 16; 1849 May 14.
Ritchie, Thomas [?] 1846 Apr. 2; 1851 July 20.
Rivers. Surveying 1837 Dec. 29; 1837 Dec. 31.
Rives, William Cabell 1838 May 26
Roads. France 1830 Dec. 21
Roads. Italy 1830 Nov. 5
Roads. North Carolina 1859 Feb. 27; 1861 Feb. 6.
Roads. South Carolina 1826 Feb. 22
Robeson, George Maxwell 1870 Sept. 16; 1870 Sept. 29; 1871 Nov. 1.
Robinson, Moncure 1844 July 26
Rock Island Mining Company 1866 Dec. 6; 1867 Mar. 28; 1867 Aug. 30; 1867 Oct. 24; 1868 Jan. 29; 1870 Feb. 13; 1870 Feb. 24; 1870 Apr. 11; 1870 June 18; 1870 July 25; 1870 Nov. 27[?].
Rocks. Igneous 1844 Feb. 6
Rodgers, John (1773-1838) [?], 1837 Dec. 31
Rodgers, John (1812-1882) 1870 Aug. 25; 1870 Sept. 13.
Rogers, Henry J. 1862 Aug. 7
Roosevelt, Nicholas J. 1849 Apr. 27
Rope 1843 Jan. 8; 1843 Dec. 2; 1843 Dec. 9; 1843 Dec. 18; 1843 Dec. 25; 1844 Jan. 28; 1844 Feb. 9; 1844 Feb. 15; 1844 Feb. 17; 1844 May 21.
Rope Makers 1843 Oct. 3
Rope Makers. Philippine Islands 1851 Jan. 27
Ross, Sir James Clark 1849 June 8
Ross, Sir John (1777-1856) 1849 June 26
Rowan, Stephen Clegg 1870 Aug. 25; 1870 Sept. 13.
Rubber Industry and Trade Printed Material: 1852 May 22
Ruger, Thomas Howard 1865 May 28
Russia. Foreign Relations. Hawaii, 1851 Mar. 28
Russia. Navy. Officers 1837 Dec. 21
Rutherfurd, Lewis Morris [?], Note on Letter to: 1859 June 30; Note on Letter to: 1859 Aug. 20.
Sabine, Sir Edward 1842 Oct. 18; 1849 June 14.
St. Catherine['s] Mining Company, Late 1853-1855 Apr. (scattered); 1856 Apr. 21; 1856 Apr. 23; 1856 June 30.
Salado River. Floods 1851 Jan. 27
San Martín, José de 1823 Jan.[?]
Santa Anna, Antonio López de, 1836 May 5
Sartiges, Etienne Gilbert Eugène, Vicomte de Letter to: 1852 May 3; 1852 May 3 (with letter of same date).
Saunders, Romulus Mitchell 1859 July 10
Savannah River 1837 Dec. 29; 1837 Dec. 31.
Schenck, Robert Cumming 1863 Apr. 1; 1870 July 9.
Schofield, John McAllister 1865 May 28; 1865 June 20.
Schools and Academies. Hawaii. Hilo, 1846 Oct. 3
Schools and Academies. Maryland. Baltimore. Peabody Institute Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p. 266
Schools and Academies. Maryland. Annapolis. United States Naval Academy 1826 Jan. 26; 1847 Mar. 10; 1847 Apr. 12; 1847 Apr. 26; 1847 May 23; 1847 June 6; 1847 June 20; 1847 July 7; 1847 Dec. 11; 1848 Jan. 27; 1849 Oct. 10; 1857 June 8; 1860 May 28.
Schools and Academies. Massachusetts. Cambridge. Lawrence Scientific School 1849 Sept. 6; 1850 Aug. 7; 1850 Sept. 9; 1850 Oct. 11; 1850 Nov. 7; 1851 Jan. 2.
Schools and Academies. North Carolina. Charlotte [?]. North Carolina Military Institute 1872 Jan. 10
Scientists 18440 Nov. 8
Scott, Winfield 1852 Nov. 4; 1852 Nov. 5.
Sea Water. Density 1859 Aug. 19 (enclosed with letter of Aug. 21); Miscellany: 1845.
Seabrook, Whitemarsh B. 1851 Nov. 3
Sealing Volume: Account Book for Ship O'Cain, 1823
Seamen 1825 Dec. 14
Secession 1850 June 19; 1851 Nov. 3; 1860 Nov. 27; 1860 Dec. 14; 1860 Dec. 21; 1860 Dec. 29.
Secession. District of Columbia. Washington 1862 Oct. 18; 1863 May 22.
Secession. North Carolina 1860 Nov. 23; 1861 Feb. 6.
Secession. South Carolina 1848 Nov. 6; 1850 May 7; 1851 Feb. 5; 1861 Feb. 6.
Secession. Virginia 1861 Feb. 6
Sedgwick, Charles Baldwin 1863 Feb. 18; 1863 Feb. 24 (enclosed with letter of Feb. 25); 1863 Mar. 10; 1863 May 20.
Sermons 1850 May 6
Servants. Irish 1830 Sept. 2[?]
Servants. New York 1830 Sept. 2[?]
Seward, William Henry 1849 Mar. 7; 1849 Apr. 27; 1863 Jan. 30; 1863 Feb. 18; 1863 Mar. [?]; Writings: "The Surrender of Mason and Slidell," pp. 1-2.
Shaler, William 1830 July 17
Shields, Benjamin Glover 1848 May 31
Ships. Alabama. CSS 1862 Nov. 4; 1862 Nov. 24; 1862 Dec. 3; 1862 Dec. 12; 1863 Jan. 2; 1863 Jan. 12 (2); 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Feb. 28; 1863 Mar. 16; 1863 Mar. 27; 1863 Apr. 13; 1863 May 28; 1863 June 4.
Ships. Albany. USS 1847 Oct. 26; 1847 Dec. 11; 1848 Jan. 19; 1848 Feb. 21; 1848 Mar. 13; 1848 Mar. 17; 1848 Apr. 5; 1848 Apr. 25; 1848 Aug. 29.
Ships. Bark Galileo (United States) 1850 Mar. 16
Ships. Boston. USS 1830 July 7; 1830 July 17; 1830 Dec. 6.
Ships. Brandywine. USS 1850 Mar. 16; 1850 July 24.
Ships. C.S.A. 1862 Oct. 27
Ships. Chile 1825 Dec. 14
Ships. Cumberland. USS 1844 Sept. 30
Ships. Dolphin. USS 1850 June 9; 1850 June 23.
Ships. Dona Maria Segunda (Portuguese) 1850 Oct. 31
Ships. Experiment. HMS 1851 Mar. 31
Ships. Fairfield. USS 1830 Oct. 4; 1830 Oct. 12; 1830 Nov. 9; 1830 Dec. 6; 1830 Dec. 8; 1831 Jan. 30.
Ships. Florida. CSS 1863 Jan. 30 (2); 1863 Feb. 3; 1863 Feb. 10; 1863 Feb. 11; 1863 Mar. [?]; 1863 Apr. 13; 1863 May 29 (part of letter of May 28).
Ships. Flying Fish. USS 1838 Sept. 1; 1840[?] Mar.; 1840[?] early Dec. [?]; 1841 Oct. 12.
Ships. Fort William (East Indian) 1851 Oct. 22 (with letter of Oct. 9[?])
Ships. Gertrude. USS Financial Papers: 1865 [?]
Ships. Hattingner 1843 Mar. 13
Ships. Independence. USS 1849 May 25
Ships. Indianola. USS 1863 Mar. [?]
Ships. Jacob Bell. USS 1863 Mar. [?]
Ships. John Adams. USS 1848 Feb. 21
Ships. Juniata. USS 1863 Jan. 27 (enclosed with letter of Jan. 28; 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Jan. 28 (2); 1863 Feb. 24; 1863 Feb. 28 (and enclosure); 1863 Mar. 20; 1863 Mar. [?]; 1863 Apr. 13; 1863 Apr. 19; 1863 Apr. 27; 1863 May 7 (part of letter of May 5).
Ships. Lewis, 1827[?] Mar. 7
Ships. Lexington. USS 1850 May 10
Ships. Marion. USS 1849 Dec. 26; 1849 Dec. 30; 1850 Jan. 9; 1850 Jan. 11; 1850 Jan. 14; 1850 Jan. 21; 1850 Jan. 27; 1850 Mar. 17 (on letter of May 23); 1850 Mar. 28; 1850 Apr. 21; 1850 May 10; 1850 May 31; 1850 June 23; 1850 July 24; 1850 Sept. 2; 1850 Sept. 14; 1850 Oct. 2
Ships. Minnesota. USS 1862 Oct. 19
Ships. Mississippi. USS 1845 June 11; 1845 Aug. 6; 1845 Nov. 19; 1845 Nov. 23; 1845 Dec. 12; 1846 Jan. 4 (on letter of Dec. 31, 1845); 1848 Jan. 23.
Ships. Missouri. USS 1863 Apr. 3
Ships. Monitor. USS 1863 Jan. 9
Ships. New Ironsides[?]. USS 1863 Jan. 12
Ships. Niagara. USS Miscellany: 1862 [?]
Ships. O'Cain (United States) Volume: Account Book for Ship O'Cain, 1823
Ships. Oregon. USS 1840 Oct. 18; 1841 Oct. 12.
Ships. Peacock. USS 1838 Sept. 16; 1840 Oct. 18; 1840 early Dec. [?]; 1841 Oct. 12; 1851 May 30; Miscellany: 1838.
Ships. Peterhoff. USS 1863 Apr. 16; 1863 Apr. 19; 1863 Apr. 27; 1863 May 6; 1863 May 7 (part of letter of May 5); Financial Papers: 1865 [?].
Ships. Philadelphia (United States), 1852 Jan. 23; 1852 Mar. 3; 1852 Mar. 6 (enclosed with letter of 1852 Mar. 13).
Ships. Plymouth. USS 1850 June 9; 1850 June 23; 1850 July 24; 1851 July 9; 1851 Sept. 15[?]; 1851 Oct. 9[?]; 1851 Nov. 17.
Ships. Porpoise. USS 1837 June 30; 1837 Dec. 1; 1838 Apr. 4; 1838 May 19; 1838 June 18; 1838 Sept. 1; 1840 Mar.; 1840 early Dec.[?]; 1840 Dec. 2; 1856 Feb. 2; 1856 Feb. 7; Legal Papers: 1857.
Ships. Princeton (First). USS 1846 Jan. 4 (letter of 1845 Dec. 31)
Ships. Raritan. USS 1846 Aug. 26; 1846 Sept. 5; 1846 Sept. 9.
Ships. Reamy, 1863 Jan. 30
Ships. Relief. USS 1835 June 1; 1839 May 22; 1839 June 3; 1839 June 12; 1839 [?].
Ships. Rhode Island. USS 1863 Mar. [?]
Ships. Sabine. USS 1859 Aug. 16; 1859 Oct. 21.
Ships. St. Louis. USS 1850 Mar. 16
Ships. San Jacinto. USS 1862 Dec. 12; 1863 Feb. 18.
Ships. Santiago de Cuba. USS 1863 Jan. 12; 1863 Mar. 6.
Ships. Saratoga. USS 1850 July 25; 1851 July 9; 1851 July 20; 1851 Oct. 9[?].
Ships. Sea Gull. USS 1838 Sept. 1
Ships. Sea Serpent (United States) 1851 Oct. 22 (with letter of Oct. 9[?])
Ships. Sea Witch (United States) 1850 Dec. 3
Ships. Sonoma. USS 1862[?] Sept. 30
Ships. Susquehanna. USS 1851 July 31; 1851 Sept. 15[?]; 1851 Oct. 9[?]; 1851 Nov. 17.
Ships. Tioga. USS 1862[?] Sept. 30
Ships. Trent (British) Writings: "The great international question"
Ships. Tuscarora. USS 1863 May 28
Ships. Vanderbilt. USS 1862 Dec. 12; 1863 Jan. 9; 1863 Jan. 27 (enclosed with letter of Jan. 28); 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Mar. 14; 1863 Mar. 15; 1863 Apr. 3; 1863 May 31; 1863 June 17.
Ships. Vincennes. USS 1838 Sept. 2; 1838 Sept. 16; 1850 Mar. 17 (on letter of May 23); 1856 Feb. 7.
Ships. Virginia. CSS 1863 Jan. 9; 1863 Jan. 18.
Ships. Virginia. USS 1850 Aug. 17
Ships. Wachusett. USS 1862 Sept. 30; 1862 Dec. 5; 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan. 27 (enclosed with letter of Jan. 28); 1863 Jan. 28 (2); 1863 Jan. 30; 1863 Feb. 24; 1863 Apr. 13; Miscellany: 1860s[?].
Ships. Water Witch. USS 1847 Dec. 11
Ships. Winfield Scott. USS 1852 Jan. 10
Shipwrecks. New York 1837 Jan. 7
Shubrick, William Branford 1837 Dec. 15; 1849 June 24; 1856 Dec. 19; 1862 Sept. 19; 1862 Oct. 1; 1862 Oct. 18; 1862 Oct. 22; 1862 Nov. 14; 1862 Nov. 30; 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Jan. 28; 1863 Mar. 10; 1863 Apr. 8.
Shufeldt, Robert Wilson (1822-1895), 1863 Apr. 19; 1863 Apr. 23.
Stillman, Benjamin (1779-1864) [?], 1853 June 25; 1853 July 26.
Stillman, Benjamin (1816-1885), 1850 Dec. 23; 1851.
Silver Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Silver Hill Mine 1856 Oct. 19
Simpson, Sir George 1840 Oct. 18
Slave Criminals 1849 Nov. 15; 1849 Nov. 17.
Slave Sales and Purchases. District of Columbia. Washington 1854 Dec. 14
Slave Sales and Purchases. North Carolina, 1849 Aug. 18
Slaveowners. South Carolina 1838 Jan. 19
Slavery. British Guiana 1835 Jan. 14
Slavery. United States 1834 July 16; 1850 Feb. 3; 1851 Jan. 15.
Slavery. United States. Northern Opinion, 1848 Apr. 14
Slaves. Emancipation 1834 July 16; 1835 Jan. 14.
Slaves. Georgia 1850s